Orange
Orange字幕组
Orange字幕组  原创翻译
Orange字幕组原创翻译
更多精彩美剧请关注我们的微博
翻译\h卡斯
翻译\h卡斯调教者纯粹
翻译\hFriday
翻译\hZhikaimail
校对\h狼尾
时间轴 Libsu苏苏\h包砸
后期 Libsu苏苏\h包砸
逃往\h欧洲
恐怖主义威胁
时\h事
文\h化
环\h境
政\h治
健\h康\h\h\h\h\h\h经\h济\h\h\h\h战\h争\h\h\h\h药\h物\h\h\h\h医\h疗
人\h权\h\h\h\h\h\h不\h平\h等\h\h\h\h公\h正
恶
这没有住所 没有生活设施
实际上 这什么都没有
对叙利亚难民说不
肖恩 史密斯\hVICE创始人
土耳其叙利亚边界
阿克恰卡莱 土耳其
艾哈迈德 谢哈布 埃尔丁
通讯记者
2015年6月14日
维兹哈达
叙利亚难民
那不停的有炮击和交火（叙利亚语）
我们穿过那的时候 正好有场战争
我们不得不趴在地上 因为那里有狙击手
我们困在那三个小时 直到战争停止我们才能穿越
你随时会死
土耳其\h苏鲁克难民营
我们在这待了十个月了
法蒂玛    叙利亚难民
我们一点钱也没有了
看 我儿子生病了
我带他们去医院 但他们不收治我们
我很绝望 我每天祈祷一千次快点让我死掉吧
爱琴海
莱斯博斯岛
希俄斯岛
摩斯岛
科斯岛
土耳其\h伊兹密尔
穆萨\h叙利亚难民
阿马尔\h叙利亚难民
我哥以前是个士兵 他不得不从军队中逃跑
我被迫前往土耳其 因为政府每个人都抓
我们知道政府会让我代替我哥参军
我谁都不想杀
你是不想死在战场吗
还是只因为你不想杀人
我不想杀人
死是一回事 但是杀戮是另一回事
你自己害怕吗
我要是说不怕 那就是在撒谎
没人不害怕
所以我们要去通向欧洲的大门
但是在你到达欧洲之前 你一直与死神为伴
隐藏摄像机
-你好- 你好
这的情况越来越糟糕了 所以你想离开了 是吗
非常想
船上一般有多少人
40,41,38,39我们一般就载这么多人
我们一般也带三四个孩子
我们也听说 不知道是不是真的
就是乘客自己开船 那到底由谁来开呢
这不是问题的 船就控制左右就行了
又不是开飞机
隐藏摄像机
谁是船长
穆萨是
我会选你
你来开船
我不知道要怎么开船
我操作给你看 别担心
我会给你一把刀
当你看到希腊海岸守卫
你必须用刀刺破你的船
爱情海 近土耳其
一个接一个
一个接一个 不然我要揍人了
驾驶员
我们走
停一下 停一下
里面进水了
兄弟 这里有太多水了
太多了
古特瑞斯  难民署高级专员
希腊\h科斯岛
为了这些孩子的未来 我们愿意冒险
要是只有我和我丈夫的话 我们就死在那算了
希腊\h莫瑞亚难民中心
希腊科斯岛\h收容所
我们这有太多的病号需要处理
虽然不是发射火箭 但我要说这些人的急需生存补给
但是这什么也没有
范吉利斯 阿法农达基斯    全科医生
这没有供应水源 没有居所 没有基本生活设施
没有厕所
实际上 这什么也没有
希腊\h雅典
阿马尔  叙利亚难民
欢迎来到希腊
我在这已经过了四五个月没钱的生活了
有时我有吃的 有时我没有
有段时间 我在公园睡了一个月
我去了马其顿四次
四次我都被警察逮捕 然后遣返
在马其顿 我们被袭击 被枪射击
我也不能被再次送回去
如果最终还是回到这 我可能会自杀
就这样
雅典
希腊
马其顿
波利卡斯特罗
塞萨洛尼基
希腊 波利卡斯特罗
你今天准备走多远
幸运的话 走到那要二十五到三十公里
希腊 马其顿边界
希腊  艾夫索诺伊
汉堡
德国
法兰克福市
慕尼黑
维也纳
布达佩斯
贝尔格莱德
雅典
匈牙利\h扎卡尼
他们告诉我们 奥地利不会接受我们这种难民
不 他们只接受一小部分人
所以你将会一直到德国去
或找其他的路子
法国\h巴黎
2015年11月13日
难民危机
德国 奥地利边界
利萨尔斯堡 奥地
我听说在德国
越来越难接纳我们了
但是我不清楚内部原因
所以我们现在等着
德国\h柏林
这些是我的证明 有人能看看吗
反对难民集会
坚决抵制难民开放政策
他们的策略是 一块一块蚕食我们的国家
现在他们那些移民正在冲击我们的人口和经济
德国\h茨维考
他们很多人在营地外抗议
他们袭击营地
他们讨厌难民 他们不喜欢我们
不管我们去哪
都是这样的境况
利比亚
尼日利亚
德国总理安格拉 默克尔
肖恩 史密斯
VICE创始人
恐怖主义威胁
巴黎圣母院
法国 巴黎
兄弟姐妹们
48小时前
巴黎刚刚经历了
有史以来最沉重的时刻
男人和女人们
被
残忍的杀害
吉安娜 托博尼
VICE 通讯员
2015年11月13日
我们不该经历这些
法国不该经历这些
太伤人心了
法国总统
弗朗索瓦 奥朗德
周五晚发生在巴黎
临近法兰西体育场的袭击
属于战争行为
叙利亚已经成为世界上已知
最大的恐怖组织工厂
现在 我们需要采取更大规模的空中打击
把伊斯兰主义者驱逐出境
ISIS新兵招募视频
我们来自加入ISIS的法国伊斯兰同胞
你们还在等什么 加入我们
请求支援 正在发生枪战
加利福尼亚州 圣贝纳迪诺
2015年12月2日
枪手可能位于
停车场 并持有一把机枪
有人受伤 请派医疗人员
至少有20人受伤
即时新闻
14人在圣贝纳迪诺大规模枪战中丧生
恐袭联线
泰德 科鲁兹参议员
德州总统候选人
唐纳德 特朗普
前总统候选人
国家舆论呼吁停止接受叙利亚难民
在梅丽登枪击案后清真寺开门做礼拜
即时新闻  两人因损坏伯灵顿清真寺公共设施被捕
伯灵顿伊斯兰教总部
来克星敦130街
德克萨斯州  达拉斯市
德州达拉斯市理查森清真寺
艾瑞克 福克斯
牧师
伊莱 佐尼 教士
麦克 沃特斯
牧师
对叙利亚难民说不
西蒙 文森特
前美国海军陆战队队员
这些人都不是逃到圣贝纳迪诺的难民
冤冤相报何时了
政府官员格雷格 阿伯特
德州
难民议案表决
难民被拒
6名叙利亚难民预计将于今日达到达拉斯
你好
亲一下 亲一下
看到了什么 孙儿
法伊兹
叙利亚难民
首先就是对于未来可能发生的事情都感到害怕
没有安全感
随时都可能遭到炮击
随时都可能有空袭
我们亲眼目睹家人和朋友被枪杀
我外甥女很年轻 才28岁
她的头部中弹死了
这就是现实
我们来这开始新的生活
这比过去的生活好很多
我想找份工作好好过日子
我希望我和我的子女都能有份工作
希望我的孙儿将来也能有工作
我希望我们能自由和有尊严的生活
叙利亚难民和申请避难者人数
欧洲 EUROPE
瑞典 SWEDEN
塞尔维亚 SERBIA
德国 GERMANY
奥地利 AUSTRIA
匈牙利 HUNGARY
北美 NORTH AMERICA
美国 UNITED STATES
非洲 AFRICA
2015年12月7日
众议员 麦克 麦克考尔
德州国土安全委员会主席
美国参议院叙利亚难民法案以60票赞成通过
ISIS招募视频
招募方法
纽约反恐警察局
乔 米勒 副局长
纽约反恐信息警察局
人 权
支持特朗普
逃往\h欧洲
本期节目
This week on Vice.
将讲述欧洲爆发的难民危机
Europe's exploding refugee crisis.
我们现在所处位置是土耳其的边境
We're here on the turkish side of the border,
但穿过边境 你可以看到一座仍被ISIS控制的城市
But just right across there, you can see Tell Abyad
泰勒艾卜耶德
which is still under isis's control.
这种地缘政治的后果
And then, the geopolitical consequences
体现在最近的巴黎恐怖袭击事件
of the recent terrorist attacks in Paris.
我们正在巴黎圣母院门前
We're right in front of Notre Dame,
这是枪击案过去的几天后
this is really the first big vigil.
的第一个大型守夜祈祷
Since the shooting just a couple days ago.
我看见这里的标语写着 向叙利亚难民说不
I saw the sign here that says "say no to Syrian refugees"?
我们国家的难民越少越好
The less of 'em in this country, the better.
叙利亚内战让暴力事件不断恶化
The spiraling violence caused by the civil war in Syria
已经触发了二战后最大的难民危机
Has touched off the worst refugee crisis since world war ii.
整整450万叙利亚人开始逃亡
Fully 4.5 million Syrians have fled,
其中大部分逃向了安全的欧洲
With many headed towards the safety of Europe.
我们跟随这些难民
We follow some of these refugees on their
踏上坎坷的现代迁徙之路
perilous trail of modern migration.
我们现在所处位置是土耳其的边境
We're here on the turkish side of the border.
这里的人们是安全的 过着日复一日的生活
People here are safe, going about their day-to-day lives.
但穿过边境 你可以望到一座仍被ISIS控制的城市
But just right across there, you can see tell Abyad,
泰勒艾卜耶德
Which is still under ISIS's control.
它已经被控制超过一年了
It has been for well over a year now.
他们已经集中在这里数日了
They've been gathering there for days,
等待着进入土耳其的时机
Waiting to cross into Turkey,
渴望着逃离战争和所谓的伊斯兰国
Hoping to escape the war and the Islamic state.
我们采访了一个家庭
We talked to one family that
他们正设法安全地越过边境
managed to make it across safely
整个叙利亚北边境都与土耳其接壤
Turkey shares Syria's entire northern border,
土方正努力着手
And its struggle to deal with the
安置目前超过250万
more than 2.5 million refugees
跨过边境的难民
who've crossed over so far.
我们所处的位置距离叙利亚只有几公里
We're here just a couple of kilometers away from Syria.
这是土耳其最大的难民营
This is Turkey's largest refugee camp.
超过25000人蜗居在这里
There are over 25,000 people here.
但像这类难民营
Camps like this one were only
仅仅治标不治本
meant to be a temporary solution,
叙利亚无休止的暴力事件
But the endless violence in Syria
让难民们
Means that most of these refugees
永远不能重回家园
will never be a able to go home.
绝望让难民们试图逃离难民营
People are so desperate to get out of these camps,
大多数逃离的难民把他们的目光投向了欧盟国家
That many of them set their sights on the European union,
他们认为这是他们过上好日子的最好机会
Which they see as their best chance for a better life.
去年 超过800000的难民试图逃向欧洲
Last year, more than 800,000 refugees tried to get to Europe
他们搭乘危险的偷渡船只
By making a dangerous boat trip
来到最近的希腊群岛
to the closest Greek islands.
超过3700人淹死在
And across the Mediterranean,
渡过地中海的途中
more than 3,700 people drowned.
我们采访了一位
We talked to one syrian refugee who
正准备偷渡的人
was preparing to make the crossing.
穆萨想去投靠他的兄弟阿马尔
Musa hoped to join his brother Ammar,
阿马尔已经成功偷渡到了希腊
who'd already made it to Greece.
走私者已经从偷渡中
Smugglers have turned this journey
赚取了约十亿美元
into a billion-dollar business,
穆萨需要花约1000美元
And Musa had to pay about a thousand
来逃离战争的世界
dollars to secure world war.
在他正忙于讨价还价时 我找到了他
I went with him as he negotiated the deal.
那天夜晚 其他难民也在为了同样的目的
That night, as other refugees lined the streets
在街上徘徊着
to make the same journey,
走私者接到穆萨后
Musa was picked up by a smuggler and
介绍了偷渡过程中许多可怕的事项
given some frightening instructions.
他们的船总是驶向希腊水域
The reason they sink their own boat in Greek waters,
是因为在联合国决议案下
Is because under a UN resolution,
希腊海岸警卫队
The Greek coast guard would be
被强制要求去救援这些乘客
forced to rescue the passengers.
并护送他们去欧盟
And bring them to The EU.
但在他们成功到达希腊之前
But before they made it to the Greek side,
船只已经开始下沉
The boat started sinking on its own.
在海里漂浮数小时后
After hours adrift at sea,
土耳其海岸警卫队把他们打捞起来
The refugees were spotted by the Turkish
并送回土耳其
coast Guard and taken back to Turkey.
为了更好的明白造成这场大规模迁移的原因
To better understand what's driving this mass migration,
我们采访了一位
We spoke to one of the top
危机应对最高决策人
policymakers dealing with the crisis,
安东尼奥 古特雷斯
Antonio Guterres,
直到一月份他还担任着
Who until january was the UN's
难民事务高级专员
high Commissioner for Refugees.
这次叙利亚和伊拉克出现的重大危机
It's clear that the mega-crisis in Syria and Iraq
已经成为二战以来
Became the worst humanitarian situation
人道主义史上最差的境况
since the second world war.
这已经变成了灾难
It's a catastrophic situation.
人们会说 我们呆在这里会在劫难逃
People said, "well, we are doomed here,"
所以加快了去欧洲的脚步
And so the movement into Europe accelerated.
我还记得一开始和我谈话的一位难民
I remember talking to the refugees in the beginning,
他们说 我们很快就会回家
They were saying, "soon we'll go back home.
我们肯定会回到家园
We are sure we will go back home."
但希望开始渐渐消散
And then slowly, slowly, this hope has been vanishing
他们在黑暗中已经看不到光明
As they don't see light at the end of the tunnel.
看不到重回叙利亚的希望
With no hope of returning to Syria,
每天越来越多的难民到达希腊
More and more refugees are arriving in Greece each day.
有些人可能成功到达欧洲
These refugees may have made it to Europe,
但更多的却陷入更糟糕的境况
But for many of them the conditions here are actually worse.
一切变得如此绝望
It's become so desperate, that abandoned
旅馆已经不堪重负 然后变成了简易过渡房
hotels have become makeshift shelters.
最近几年
Greece has been in, the last few years,
希腊的经济形式变得非常困难
a very difficult economic situation.
失业率极高
They have levels of unemployment that are appalling.
希腊并没有准备好
Greece is less prepared
去接纳和消化这么多人口
to be able to properly receive and accept this population.
有一位难民已经感受这种困难
One refugee who's learned that lesson the hard way is
他就是比穆萨早几个月
Musa's brother Ammar, who left
离开叙利亚的兄弟阿马尔
Syria a few months before him.
他已经陷入这样的不稳定状况快一年了
He's been stuck here in limbo for almost a year.
如果再试一次 你会害怕吗
So, are you scared to try again?
阿马尔同其他难民一起
Ammar joined hundreds of other refugees
坐上了往北的火车 去向马其顿的边境
On a train headed north, toward the Macedonian border,
这里离德国只有一步之遥
And one step closer to Germany.
在波利卡斯特 他们开始了徒步迁移
At Polikastro, they continued on foot.
阿马尔离开了大部队
Ammar split from the group,
经过连续两天的行走
And after walking for two straight days,
他平安的进入了马其顿
He crossed safely into Macedonia.
但那些留下的人们就不那么走运了
But those he left behind weren't so lucky.
我们终于到达了边界 这里可以看到
Finally we get to the border and there are
数百名难民
hundreds of refugee
边界的这边是希腊
This is on the Greek side of the border,
沿途你可以看到很多马其顿的军队
And just along the way, you see the Macedonian army.
他们已经无数次尝试越过边界
They've tried to cross several times,
每次越界 那些军队就会立即赶到
And every time they cross they get there,
无论马其顿的军队
And whether or not the Macedonian army
有没有强行将他们赶回去
actually pushes them back forcefully,
他们都无法入境 因为边境已经封锁
They find themselves back here because the border's closed.
几天后 形势紧张了起来
Just a few days later, tensions here exploded
为了穿过欧洲
And across Europe,
边防安保已被大批难民淹没
refugees overwhelmed border security by the thousands.
与此同时
At the same time,
德国宣布会接受更多的避难者
Germany said it would accept more asylum seekers,
所以有国家已经开始关闭他们的边境
So individual countries began sealing their borders
难民选择搭乘火车去往德国
And shuttling refugees towards Germany by train.
当你与一些难民谈话时
When you talk to some of these refugees,
当你开始提问时
When you ask them questions,
他们也会向你询问
They end up asking you as many
会提很多的问题
questions as you're asking them,
因为他们对于将要去的地方
Because they don't have any idea where they're going really
以及他们即将要面对的东西 都一无所知
or what they're going to do when they get there.
紧张气氛不断加剧
But tensions have been mounting.
在巴黎遭受恐怖袭击后
After the terrorist attacks in aris,
中欧国家开始严格限制
Central European countries began severely restricting
入境的人
Who could pass through their borders.
塞尔维亚 马其顿克罗地亚 斯洛文尼亚宣布
Serbia, Macedonia, Croatia, and Slovenia announced
它们将开始遣返外来移民
They will turn back economic migrants.
愤怒的难民们
Outraged refugees staged
用可怕的示威游行来作为回应
a gruesome demonstration in response,
例如 将嘴巴缝起来
Sewing their lips together in protest.
那些成功越境的人发现
And those who have made it through
即便德国也难以承受这种危机
have found that even Germany is overwhelmed by the crisis.
在连接奥地利与德国的桥上
This is the bridge connecting Austria and Germany.
你可以看见许多等待越境的难民
You can see tons of refugees waiting here to cross over.
即使他们对旅程的前方
Even though this is hopefully the end of
充满希望 他们却还是在等
their journey, they still waiting.
即使在德国境内
But even inside Germany,
成千上万的难民仍在等待
There are hundreds of thousands of refugees already waiting.
事实上 在2015年
In fact, in 2015,
一百万难民逃向欧洲
One million refugees fled to Europe,
没有一个国家能单独接纳如此巨大的人口
An influx that no country could handle alone.
而且许多外国人的加入
And the arrival of so many foreigners in
已经引发了德国人的强烈抗议
Germany has sparked a growing backlash.
德累斯顿出现了数千人的游行
Thousands marched in Dresden
支持反伊斯兰的PEGIDA(反西方伊斯兰化的爱国欧洲人)行动
in support of the anti-Islam movement PEGIDA.
他们都是参与抵制运动的抗议者
They're part of a movement protesting
他们担心德国文化将受到侵袭
What they see as the threat to german culture.
于此同时 在数千英里外的
Meanwhile, after thousands of miles
无数个过境点
and countless border crossings,
阿马尔长达一年的跋涉终于在
Ammar's yearlong journey had finally come to an end
一个德国的小城结束
in a small city in germany.
但他告诉我们 就算被允许进入欧洲
But he told us that being accepted into europe
也不代表就能被当地人民接纳
doesn't mean being accepted by the people who live here.
战争让叙利亚上演了新版的出埃及记
The war in Syria, and the Exodus it's causing,
而这场战争仅仅是导致
is just one of dozens of conflicts
全球六千万人民无家可归的
that have created a staggering 60 million
许多冲突中的一个
displaced people around the world
严重的危机
A profound crisis
已经影响到欧洲政治局势
that is already reshaping the political landscape in europe
甚至牵涉到美国
and even in the United states.
如果这种状况持续 未来会怎样
If things continue this way, what does the future hold?
我认为全世界很多决策者们
I think many decision-makers in the world,
在国内受到实质性影响之前
refuse to see the reality that is coming
都对现实视而不见
until that reality enters their doors.
我们已经发现新的冲突在急剧增多
We have seen a multiplication of new conflicts.
过去 我们的战争发生在国家之间
In the past, we had wars between states
或者政府和反叛组织之间
or between a government and a rebel group.
但是在现今很多国家
But now in many countries,
受到多种多样的力量干预
you have a multiplicity of actors.
有政府力量 也有国际力量
You have government forces, international forces,
还有民族武装 宗教民兵 以及政治民兵
ethnic militias, religious militias, political militias,
它们都糅合在一起
All operating in the same scenarios.
各种冲突都相互牵连
and all the conflicts are getting interlinked.
从尼日利亚到阿富汗 我们看到战争
From Nigeria to Afghanistan, we see fighters
从一个国家到另一个国家
going from one scenario to another.
这让我们看到世界变了
It shows how the world is changing,
变得更加危险
How it's becoming much more dangerous
更多的人陷入苦难
and how much more people are suffering.
我们也看到人们排外情绪的爆发
And we are also seeing eruptions of xenophobia.
比如 就有欧洲人发表言论
When, for instance, someone says in Europe
说不欢迎穆斯林难民
that Muslim refugee are not welcome
这给出一个信号 表示是达伊沙
It gives a pretext for the propaganda that Daesh makes
导致了西方世界对
about the attitude of the Western world
穆斯林世界的态度
in relation to the Muslim world.
不能继续这样
This cannot go on.
如果持续这个状态 所有人都会恐慌
If this goes on, everybody will be threatened.
现在的叙利亚难民潮使得
Now the flood of refugees coming out of Syria
人道主义面临重大危机
has been one of the largest humanitarian crises
但是全世界的态度却在一夜之间转变了
But the global response to it transformed overnight
因为巴黎ISIS袭击事件中的一位恐怖分子
due to suspicions that a member of the ISIS attacks on paris
被怀疑是通过伪装成难民入境的
may have entered the country posing as a refugee,
这在世界范围内引起了众多
which has sparked a number of complex and
复杂的反对情绪
contradictory reactions around the world.
我们正在巴黎圣母院前
We're right in front of Notre Dame,
这是为几天前刚发生的枪击事件进行的
and this is really the first big vigil since the shooting
第一个大规模守夜祈祷
just a couple days ago,
成百上千的民众走出家门聚集在这里
And hundreds of people have come out here.
而此时仍有持枪歹徒没有落网
There are still gunmen on the loose that they haven't located
每个人看起来仍然很不安
Everyone seems to be still very much on edge.
在2015年12月 ISIS声称
In november of 2015, ISIS claimed responsibility
对西方世界自911之后的
for one of the deadliest terrorist attacks
这场致命恐怖袭击负责
committed in the West since 9/11.
恐怖分子包括武装枪手和自杀爆炸袭击者
Armed gunmen and suicide bombers,
其中至少两人据传
including at least two rumored to have
是通过假扮难民进入欧洲境内的
to have entered the EU posing as refugees,
他们闯入巴黎市区
stormed the city of Paris,
袭击无辜的市民
terrorizing innocent civilians
在一处音乐厅 一处体育场 以及饭店
in a concert hall, a stadium, and restaurants,
杀害了130人
Killing 130 people.
人们在地上摆放蜡烛以及鲜花
These memorials, with hundreds of people
表达对死者的悼念
putting candles and flowers down,
全城到处都能看到这样的悼念景象
are all over the city.
就在袭击发生之后
Immediately after the attacks,
法国立刻公开加大对
France began dramatically stepping up its airs strikes
伊拉克和叙利亚境内ISIS的空袭力度
against ISIS targets in Iraq and Syria.
然而空袭也产生了另一种
But air strikes tend to go hand-in-hand
激增效果
with a surge in ant
这一行动反而证明了ISIS关于
It helps to prove ISIS's contention
西方世界是在与伊斯兰教发生战争的论调
that the West is at war with Islam,
这激化了本身就有所不满的穆斯林
Which in turn helps to radicalize disaffected muslims,
可能引起新的袭击事件
and inspire new attacks.
这是一个我们所忽视的恶性循环
It's a cycle that we don't seem to be able to break,
而现在它又在美国上演
and now it's playing out here in the United States.
一对夫妻在
A married couple opened fire
圣贝纳迪诺的中心地区开枪杀人
at theinland regional center in San Bernardino.
调查显示枪击犯是
Evidence is mounting that the killers
加利福尼亚州圣贝纳迪诺市
in San Bernardino, California,
的本土伊斯兰激进分子
had become homegrown islamist radicals.
这次枪击事件紧随巴黎袭击之后
The killings, coming so soon after the Paris attacks,
这导致我们的边境被封锁
set off a call to seal our borders,
即便袭击者并不来自难民
even though the attackers were not refugees.
让难民入境是愚蠢的做法
It is lunacy to be bringing refugees into this country
他们会试图伤害美国人
who may be terrorists trying to murder Americans.
唐纳德 特朗普 发表言论称要全面禁止
Donald J Trump is calling for a total and complete shutdown
穆斯林入境美国
of Muslims entering the United States
除非众议院能够
until our country's representatives can
完全掌握状况
figure out what the hell is going on.
针对难民问题的态度已经很明显
That focus on refugees has taken root,
超过30名州长已经声明
and more than 30 governors have called
拒绝接收穆斯林难民
for a block on Syrian refugees,
尽管总统奥巴马承诺再接收一万人
In spite of President Obama's pledge to take 10,000 more.
在巴黎袭击事件发生后一个月 美国因仇视穆斯林
And across the US, reported hate crimes against Muslims
而引起的罪案就上升了两倍
tripled in the month following the Paris attacks.
在达拉斯 市民们组织武装抗议
In Dallas, civilians are organizing armed protests
防范那些他们认为
and defending against what they see
可能存在的威胁
as a threat to their communities.
我们来到达拉斯看看其中一队人的情况
So we're here with a group outside of Dallas.
他们正在为下周在一个清真寺前的
They're just prepping for a protest that they're going to do
抗议活动做演习
in front of a mosque next weekend.
我们要反复查看队员的武器
Let's go ahead and go back over some weapon safety.
确保每个人的枪是空膛
Make sure everybody's got an empty chamber.
好的
Good hook.
安全
Safe.
好的 没问题了
All right, good to go.
不错
Sweet.
我们开始第一阶段训练
We're gonna be the first stage.
如果有人试图进行破坏行为
So if someone tries to break in the line,
就会像这样上前靠近
go ahead and close up like that.
因为这次他们正等着我们
because they're going to be expecting us this time.
在清真寺内
Inside the mosque,
领拜人正召集信徒开会
we watched as the imam prepared his congregants.
我想大家都知道
Tomorrow i'm sure most of you are aware,
明天会在我们清真寺外进行集会
that there is going to be a rally outside of our mosque,
那时也会有一批全副武装的人在场
and that it's going to be a group of armed people.
我们只要做好我们该做的事情就行了
Our part is to make sure that what we're doing is correct.
因为清真寺会面临抗议活动
As the mosque braced for this protest,
宗教团体召开紧急会议
the broader religious community held a
探讨如何应对
tense meeting about how to respond.
我很担心穆斯林什么时候会发生骚乱
I am deeply concerned when Muslims are harassed.
我无法理解
I can't fathom--
韦斯 你能理解那些在礼拜日
Wes, can you fathom people with
持枪守在你教堂外的人吗
with guns outside your church on Sunday?
我是说 这太粗鲁了
I mean, it's outrageous.
当我听到一个总统候选人说
When i hear a presidential candidate say,
让人民们分类注册是个很好的方法
it's a good idea to register and label people,
那让我想起了20世纪30年代的德国
that has echoes for me of 1930s Germany.
我想起我的祖父
I think about my grandfather who was a
他是个社会活动家 接触过很多事
social activist, amongst many things,
一天晚上被三K党（美国民间仇恨团体）找上门
and one night was visited by the Klan to his home.
我祖父邀请他们的大巫师进屋喝咖啡
My grandfather invited the grand wizard in for coffee.
他对大巫师说
He wanted him to know that
是的 你可以来我家找我
"yes, you can show up at my door,
但我不会因为这样就逃跑
But you're not going to cause me to run away."
在这种时候 你不可能忍气吞声
In moments like this, you can't remain silent.
我认为人们正面临一个艰难的抉择
I think people are being challenged
去选定他们要站在一条怎样的历史路线上
to determine what side of history they're going to stand on.
我看到他们的标语是 对叙利亚难民说不
I saw the sign here that says "say no to Syrian refugees."
你也同意这句话吗
Do you also back that message?
必然同意
Absolutely.
在这个国家 他们这些人越少越好
The less of 'em in this country, the better.
作为前美国陆战队员
How does it feel to be a former US marine
同时也是穆斯林社区的一员
and a part of the Muslim community
而现在这些人正在这里进行抗议
and having these guys come up here
你是怎么想的 你并没有紧随美国做派
saying basically, you're un-American,
另外 假如你是穆斯林
and if you're a Muslim, there's a
难道就表明你更可能是恐怖分子吗
good chance that you're a terrorist?
我所知道的伊斯兰教
What they're seeing in the media
并不是他们在电视上看到的那样
is not the Islam that I know.
在战场上
The things they teach you in the
他们教会你的是
military, when you go to combat,
要把你的敌人想象成猛兽
you dehumanize your enemy so it
才能毫不留情去干掉他们
makes it easier to kill them.
现在又是这样
That's what all this is rolled up to be.
试图把穆斯林妖魔化
An attempt to dehumanize muslims,
使他们感觉并不是美国人
Make them seem like they're not american,
即便他们与其他美国人享有同样权力
Like they don't belong, when they have
他们也不属于这里
every right just like any other american
如果一个叙利亚难民杀了你的孩子
If a syrian refugee came in here and killed your kid,
你也会和我一样站在这里
You'd be over here with me.
这不是重点
That's not the point.
-重点是 -这就是你刚刚说的重点
-The point is -that's the point you just made.
-你说了叙利亚难民 -不 重点是
-You said syrian refugees. -no, the point is
ISIS成员混入了
Is that ISIS is mixing in with
叙利亚难民之中 这是事实
syrian refugees, that's a fact
-你们是在这座清真寺拜谒的吗 -没错
-Do you attend this mosque here? -Yes.
-好的 -是的 没错
-Okay. -Yes, we do.
你们怎么看这场抗议
And what do you make of the protests here?
在某种程度上 我不怪这些人
In a way, I don't blame these people.
他们中的大多数都误会了
Most of these people, they misunderstand.
伊斯兰教不代表杀人
Islam is not about killing people.
伊斯兰教不代表仇恨
Islam is not about hate.
伊斯兰教关乎着爱与和平
Islam is about love, peace.
对于ISIS的所作所为
What ISIS is doing,
很不幸 我们这些在美国的穆斯林
unfortunately, us here, Muslims in america,
是我们在替他们遭受责难
we are suffering behind that.
我的妻子由于她工作时的穿着而被人嫌恶
My wife gets harassed at work because of what she's wearing.
我的儿子 他在健身房里被人欺负
My son, he got jumped in the gym.
艾哈迈德 你想对那些欺负你
Ahmed, what would you want to tell somebody
或者不理解你们宗教的人说些什么
who bullies you or who doesn't understand your religion?
我只想说在动手和开口之前请好好想想
Just think before they do what they do and say what they say
因为我们并不全是坏人
because we're not all bad.
通常你们驾车通过这样的抗议人群时
Usually you drive past a protest like this,
你们看见荷枪实弹的人 你们可能只是觉得
you see guys with big guns, and you sort of think,
他们就是些疯狂的极端主义者
"oh, they're just crazy extremists."
但现在你们的州长
But now that you have governors and
议员和总统候选人
senators, president candidates
站出来说着同样的话
Coming out and speaking the same message,
他们似乎并未看到这种偏激
They actually don't seem that fringe anymore.
差不多同时 德州州长宣称
Around the same time, the governor of texas announced
他将试图阻止所有
That he would attempt to block all
叙利亚难民进入德州
syrian refugees from entering his state
叙利亚难民将不被允许
Syrian refugees are not going to be allowed
进入德州避难
Into the state of texas and given refuge.
尽管州长提议阻止
Despite the governor's proposed block,
仍有一家人突破限制 成功进入德州
One family was able to beat the odds.
在他们与家人重聚的第一时间
We met up with them during their very first hours in texas
我们见到了他们
as they reunited with their family.
法伊兹十个月前来到美国
Faez came to america ten months ago.
现在 在两年的分别之后
Now, after two years apart,
他的兄弟 侄子和他们一家都平安到达美国
His brother, nephew and their families have arrived safely.
大多数美国人都无法想象你们经历过什么
Most americans have no idea what you've been through.
你们是如何在叙利亚这种
How do you raise a family in a place like syria
战乱的地方撑起一个家的
the way it is right now?
传统上来讲 美国比其他国家
The US traditionally accepts more refugees
接受更多的难民
Than any other country.
但如果这些难民来自叙利亚 就像我们家庭一样
But when it comes to syrian refugees, like this family,
情况就完全相反
the opposite is true.
当其他国家已经接受成百上千
While other countries have admitted hundreds of thousands
无家可归的难民时
of displaced syrians,
美国自叙利亚战争以来只接受了约四千名难民
The US have accepted about 4,000 since the war began.
但是很多美国议员认为这都已经太多了
But some lawmakers here think even that is too many.
我们仍需采取一切手段
We also need to do everything we can to
阻止恐怖分子潜入我国境内
block terrorist pathways into our country
坚持要将这个叙利亚家庭驱逐出德州的
Congressman Michael Mccaul,
众议院议员 迈克尔 麦克考尔
Who fought to keep this syrian family from settling in texas
提出立法只能允许
Introduced legislation that would
除叙利亚和伊拉克之外的
all but block
的难民入境
from syrian and iraq.
根据现在的申请体系
The system as it is now,
如果想通过难民审查
In order for somebody to get through our refugee program--
首先 要能通过第一阶段联合国难民署的审查
First of all, less than one percent chance,
而这只有不到百分之一的机会
they'll get past the first stage with UNHCR.
然后他们要接受调查
They then are investigated,
被多个美国机构约见
interviewed by multiple US agencies
联邦调查局 国土安全部 国务院
That's the FBI, DHS, state department,
反恐单位 情报体系
Counterterrorism unit, intelligence community.
这不是个容易的过程 需要两年的时间
It's not an easy process, can take up to two years.
为什么ISIS能让一些恐怖分子通过审查
Why would ISIS send somebody through that process?
呃 这个问题很好
Well, that's a good question for ISIS,
但是我们知道他们确实这么做了
But we know that they have tried to do it.
我知道你的州最近卷入了一场
I know your state was recently embroiled in a debate
有关是否应该允许叙利亚难民
Surrounding whether or not to let
进入德州的辩论
syrian refugee families into Texas
对此 你的立场是什么
What was your stance on that?
我希望我的法案能够通过
I'm hopeful that my bill will pass,
以便我们可以再一次推行更好的审查系统
So that we can, again, put a better system in place--
那么在新的审查程序实行之前
And so you didn't want those families accepted
你不希望这些家庭通过审查
until a new vetting process was in place
他们提交了我的一份声明
Well, they submitted a statement from me
而我们现有的情报工作有一些问题
that our intelligence services have--
这是在提醒我们 他们正在试图利用漏洞
are warning that they are trying to exploit it.
但是司法机关反馈称
But the justice department came back
州政府曾列举的证据
and called the evidence that state was
只是是推测性的
putting forward uninformed and speculative.
我不想陷入这件事所有的
Well, i don't want to get into all
来龙去脉当中
the ins and outs of that case.
这应该是一个州检察长处理的案子
That's a state attorney general making his case.
我并不知道关于这个家庭的所有细节
I don't know the-- all the specifics on this family.
我理解你们在安全方面的考量 但是突然停止
I understand the security concern, but by hitting the brakes
我们国家接收难民
on accepting refugees into our country
我们是否在某种程度上拒绝了
Are we in some way closing the door
全世界中最脆弱的人们
to the most vulnerable population in the world?
在所有我们能采取的措施中
And isn't that sort of the most
这似乎最不像美国的作风
un-American thing we can be doing?
不 我认为这种保护美国人生命的做法
No, i think it's very pro-American
是非常亲美的
to protect American lives
除非国土安全部秘书长 联邦调查局局长
and I would argue that until i'm given assurance
以及国家情报委员会主管
by the secretary of Homeland, the FBI director,
都能担保这些人
the director of National Intelligence
不对我们国家构成威胁
that these people don't pose a
否则我将抗争到底
threat to our national security,
我感到不安
I'm uncomfortable.
如果我们做错了决定 人民可能会死去
If we don't do this right, Americans could die,
这就是我们试图进行阻止的原因
And that's what we're trying to stop.
众议院议员麦克考尔的提案在下议院获得了通过
Congressman McCaul's bill passed the House,
但在参议院被驳回
But failed in the Senate.
所以目前为止 我们不会阻止难民进入
So for now, we won't be closing our doors to refugees.
但现行法律的一些措辞
But the rhetoric surrounding this legislation
可能有助于恐怖分子进行招募活动
may be aiding terrorist recruitment.
唐纳德 特朗普近期关于阻止
Donald Trump's recent comments about barring
穆斯林进入美国的言论
muslims from entering the United States
已经被一个与基地组织有关的恐怖组织
are now part of a recruitment video for a
作为招募视频宣传的一部分
terror group affiliated with Al Qaeda.
在这种强烈对立的氛围中
And the idea that terror groups could seize
那些恐怖组织可能利用这种观点引发新的攻击
on this deeply polarized climate to inspire new attacks,
美国反恐部门
Has American counter-terrorism
已经在为最坏的情况做准备了
units preparing for the worst.
我们已经看到在圣贝纳迪诺发生的枪击案
We've seen what happened in San Bernardino.
所以我们现在要考虑多种方式的袭击
So we're talking about now multiple-pronged attacks
包括使用重武器和简易爆炸装置
Using heavy weapons and improvised explosives.
我们采访了纽约警察局
We spoke to the head of the NYPD's
反恐部门的领导 约翰 米勒
Counter Terrorism Unit, John Miller,
关于恐怖袭击的演变
About the evolution of the terrorist threat.
我们正处于所谓的恐怖循环之中
We're in what's being referred to as a cycle of terror.
911事件发生 我们就入侵伊拉克
9/11 happens, we invade Iraq.
ISIS兴起 我们就空袭他们
ISIS rises, we're now air-striking ISIS.
是否因为我们对恐怖分子的反应
Are we under more of a threat because
导致了我们遭受更多威胁
of how we're reacting to terrorists?
你必须要考虑到
You have to take into account that
过去的许多年中
over the last couple of years,
在世界范围内 因恐怖主义导致的死亡中
Between 65 and 85 percent of the killing
有百分之六十五到百分之八十五
worldwide in the name of terrorism
都是由两个在911事件之前不存在的
has been carried out by two groups
恐怖组织导致的
that didn't even exist before 9/11.
即伊拉克和黎凡特伊斯兰国以及博科圣地
ISIL, the Islamic State, and Boko Haram.
所以说 这个世界正在变得
So the world is getting to be,
越来越危险
continually, a more dangerous place.
这就是现实挑战
And that-- that's a real challenge.
现在对于美国的威胁
What's the current threat to the US,
或者更具体地讲 对纽约的威胁是什么
and more specifically, new york, right now?
在任何特定时间 我们都有
At any given time, we have three
三到四件要案会
or four major cases going on
演变成长期威胁
into long-term threats,
而且 尽管听起来令人不安 可这就是新常态
and, as disturbing as it may sound, is a new normal.
这种新常态意味着我们在可预见的未来
That new normal means we're going to be on high alert
要保持高度警惕
for the foreseeable future.
我们将要面临的最大问题
And the biggest question we face going forward
是我们该如何对待成千上万
is what to do about the millions of
希望在西方世界得到保护的难民
refugees who want protection in the West.
这是一个有深远影响的重要决定
It's a huge decision with far-reaching consequences,
不仅关乎那些家庭
Not just for these families,
更关乎我们的政治进程和国家架构
but for our political process and the fabric of our country.
无药可救 无法医治 无法控制
Incurable, untreatable and unstopable,
然后就是死亡
Next step is death
下期节目
On the next epsood of VICE
我们将触动底线 围绕死亡权利展开探讨
We hitted the base srrounding the right to die
为什么传统导向这么反对用药
Why is the classic leadership so oppose the to pills
从信仰的层面上讲
From our faith perspective，there is the reality
那是上帝决定的事 我们不能决定
the god is god but we are not
我认为有些人应该获得
I think these is someone should have rights
决定自己死亡的权利
to choose their own death
尽在下一期 恶
These all in the next episode VICE